The truth can't be hidden forever
Mr. Jones is a thriller, drama, history film directed by Agnieszka Holland.
In 1933, Welsh journalist Gareth Jones travels to Ukraine,
where he experiences the horrors of a famine.
Everywhere he goes he meets henchmen of the Soviet secret service who are
determined to prevent news about the catastrophe from getting out.
Stalin’s forced collectivisation of agriculture has resulted in
misery and ruin—the policy is tantamount to mass murder.
Gareth Jones, played by James Norton.
Ada Brooks, played by Vanessa Kirby.
Walter Duranty, played by Peter Sarsgaard.
George Orwell, played by Joseph Mawle.
Lloyd George, played by Kenneth Cranham.
Matthew, played by Celyn Jones.
Jones (Mr Jones in the United Kingdom; Polish: Obywatel Jones, lit.
'Citizen Jones'; Ukrainian: «Ціна правди», romanized: Tsina pravdy, lit.
'The Price of Truth') is a 2019 biographical thriller film written and
co-produced by Andrea Chalupa and directed by Agnieszka Holland.
It is based on the true story of Welsh journalist Gareth Jones, who uncovers the truth of the
devastating famine (Holodomor) in which millions died in the Ukrainian SSR, Soviet Union.
The film was selected to compete for the Golden Bear at the
69th Berlin International Film Festival.
The film explores themes of grave, based on true
story, genocide, 1930s, holodomor.
The tone is emotional and intense.